# Zekeriya Koç

- 00905438756249
- http://zekzekus.github.com/
- http://about.me/zekzekus
- zekzekus@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software (especially Python and Oracle) Developer
Skills (each row ordered by experience and knowlegde level); - Python, Javascript, PL/SQL,
Java, Ruby, Erlang, Smalltalk - Django, Flask, Ruby on Rails, Play framework, JQuery,
Backbone - Web development, Database development, Mobile Development, Desktop

Development - Oracle, Postgresql, Mysql, MS SQL Server - SQL, T-SQL - Elasticsearch, Redis, Couchdb, Riak, Mongodb - Linux, OS/X, Unix, BSD, MS Windows - Git, SVN, - Oracle Forms, Reports 6i/9i/10g

## **SKILLS**

- Python
- HTTP
- Web Development
- Oracle
- SOL
- Open Source
- Glassfish
- Ruby on Rails
- PHP
- Erlang
- Common Lisp
- Windows
- Nginx
- Git
- OOP
- Databases
- JAXWS
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Smalltalk
- Ubuntu
- JSON
- MVC
- Bash
- Software Design
- Vim

- Django
- Web Applications
- Software Development
- PL/SQL
- Java
- Web Services
- Ruby
- JavaScript
- Play Framework
- Haskell
- Linux
- Apache
- REST
- Subversion
- MySQL
- JAXB
- NetBeans
- Unix
- T-SQL
- Mobile Applications
- SOAP
- Design Patterns
- Eclipse
- Teamwork

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Metglobal

Senior Python Developer

03 / 2013 - Present

- This is company behind hotelspro.com, otel.com, tatil.com, gezi.com, dhr.com. We are redesigning, recreating whole infrastructure for these and oncoming sites.
- Part of a great team building backend infrastructure and services to support large number of high traffic hotel reservation sites.

• Working with Python, Django, Postgresql, elasticsearch etc.

#### Tim Ticaret Net Bilisim A.S.

08 / 2012 - 03 / 2013

Lead Developer

TTN is a technology (mainly software) creator company works under Turkish Exporters Assembly (TiM). TTN have responsibilities of supporting Turkish associations of exporters' (various sectors) growth.

am responsible of managing software development team which works on various size of software (mainly web apps these days) projects.

For now we are using mainly python/django/postgresql stack. Main development and deployment occures on linux based operating systems.

We are crafting high quality web sites and web applications top to bottom including design, frontend, backend, deployment phases.

Some keywords about me and my team's interests and involvements; python, django, postgresql, ubuntu server, git, uwsgi, nginx, fabric, rest apis, http etc.

## Ay Marka Mag. AS

06 / 2010 - 08 / 2012

Software Development Unit Manager

A big textile retail company includes the famous brands Network, Fabrika, Beymen Bussiness, Altınyıldız Classics, Arzu Kaprol, Que, T-box, Divarese. I am responsible of the maintenance and development processes of the ERP part of in house developed system. Main database is Oracle 10g RDBMS and Oracle Forms 6i/10g, Reports 6i/10g tools for user interface.

I made use of Oracle object system in my projects. I implemented some applications with object oriented facilities provided directly in database.

## Beymen Bo aziçi Alboy A. .

05 / 2007 - 06 / 2010

Software Projects Manager

Big textile retail company includes the brands T-box and Divarese. I was responsible all of the software projects. Maintenance of the in house developed ERP system mostly coded on Oracle database and Forms/Reports tools was my primary responsibility. My team consist of one or two developer except me.

I manage the whole implementation/migration of a new ERP system called Nebim Winner. The planning, data migrating, testing and implementation was successfully done in six months.

#### Akademi Yazılım

09 / 2006 - 05 / 2007

Software Development Specialist

Company were offering all in one solutions to big insurance companies. Oracle RDBMS, Oracle Forms/Reports tools were our main development stack. I coded directly on database with PL/SQL language. I improved my SQL experience and skills on direct database programmable objects like stored procedures, functions, packages and triggers.

#### Sampa Yazılım A..

06 / 2004 - 09 / 2006

Software Support Specialist

The company was developing software systems for all operations of municipalities. I was in a team supports customers directly. My responsibilities were; first analyze of the project,

installation, data migration, training and continuous support including data mining operations, on the fly solutions includes code modifications etc.

I experienced with Oracle developer tools very first time here. I mainly code in Oracle Forms 6i and Oracle Reports 6i tools with PL/SQL, a Pascal like procedural programming language. Also, i gained high level of SQL experience here.

## **EDUCATION**

## Anadolu Üniversitesi

2007 - 2011

Bachelor of Science (BS), Bussiness Management

## Celal Bayar Üniversitesi

2001 - 2003

Computer Programmer

TTL

#### Tuzla Anadolu Teknik Lisesi

## LANGUAGES

• English ( Professional working proficiency )

• Turkish ( Native or bilingual proficiency )

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## Smalltalk ile Yazılım Geli tirme

07 / 2007

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · <a href="http://ubuntuone.com/70WYOhLMrxRxpt9svb0qOP">http://ubuntuone.com/70WYOhLMrxRxpt9svb0qOP</a>

A guide to basics of smalltalk development with Squeak. Turkish.

## Deniz Kenarında Kısa Bir Gezinti: Seaside

02 / 2007

 $fazlamesai.net ~\cdot~ Authors: Zekeriya~Koç~\cdot~ \underline{http://ubuntuone.com/0sw8K6yhHJDLugSLRrhOoK}$ 

Turkish translation of an article about Seaside Web Framework written in Smalltalk programming language

#### Emacs ile Oracle SQL\*Plus ve "sql-mode"

01 / 2008

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · http://ubuntuone.com/3ubnc3wquY9XMYHmFmsyhA

A short article about to use emacs editor to connect oracle database and use as a interface to oracle's sql\*plus utility

## Ironpython: .NET üzerinde Python - Bölüm 1

11 / 2006

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · <a href="http://ubuntuone.com/6WNYCqGYeP2oN7113WLGBz">http://ubuntuone.com/6WNYCqGYeP2oN7113WLGBz</a>

Turkish translation of an article about Iron python an implementation of Python language that sits on top of . NET framework. Part 1

## Ironpython: .NET üzerinde Python - Bölüm 2

11 / 2006

 $fazlamesai.net ~\cdot~ Authors: Zekeriya~ Koç~ \cdot~ \underline{http://ubuntuone.com/4nkt7nvT0YbG7Q8vJ0KlVY}$ 

Turkish translation of an article about Ironpython an implementation of Python language that sits on top of .NET framework. Part 2

## Ironpython: .NET üzerinde Python - Bölüm 3

11 / 2006

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · <a href="http://ubuntuone.com/57WqaqCINhoopnp0nCSxiQ">http://ubuntuone.com/57WqaqCINhoopnp0nCSxiQ</a>

Turkish translation of an article about Ironpython an implementation of Python language that sits on top of .NET framework. Part 3

## UncommonWeb ile "Merhaba Dünya"

04 / 2007

fazlamesai.net · Authors: Zekeriya Koç · <a href="http://ubuntuone.com/37Vk27HkqLoCJxjsn9X5My">http://ubuntuone.com/37Vk27HkqLoCJxjsn9X5My</a>

A guide to the sophisticated web development framework written in Common Lisp language. Turkish.